Phil Griswold

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Contact

615-495-3912



philgriswold@me.com



https://github.com/Philgriswold



in https://www.linkedin.com/in/philgriswold



https://philgriswold.github.io/

About Me

Early in my work life, I channeled all of my curiosity and desire to create into my first love music. I followed that desire down some adventurous roads and over many peaks and valleys. At some point along the way, having already experienced many of the ups and downs of the artist life, I found myself wanting to create in a new medium - one that might chart a meaningful yet more stable journey. Software development came to me at the right time as the most fitting answer. While I find it to be challenging at times, I am fascinated by the art, the scope, and the real life application of it. I have also found that It is a world big and wide enough to find one's own space in and the most logical new place for me to park my curiosity.

Projects

THE RAMENATOR

Created an individual capstone project using React, Reactstrap, and Bootstrap called "The Ramenator" that allows users to find and review the best Ramen shops in Tokyo.

JAZZIMA

Developed an application that allows jazz fans to search what Blue Note era albums their favorite musician or collection of musicians played on based on a set of four prepopulated dropdown menus. Built the app using C# .NET and Entity Framework.

Education

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Software Development Bootcamp

BERKLEE COLLEGE OF MUSIC

Bachelor of Art in Music 2006

Software Experience

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

August 2019 - February 2020

Six-month apprenticeship program focusing on the application of full-stack web development in real life technical scenarios.

- Built web applications utilizing the building block languages for full stack development such as JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, and C#. I also learned how to navigate the intricacies of the version control platform GitHub while creating projects in class.
- Collaborated on a team project called "Welcome to Nashville" that involved learning how to fetch data from API's and creating modular JavaScript files. I was in charge of fetching and displaying useful data from the Zomato API for the application.
- Worked on a team to create a social media platform application called "Nutshell" in vanilla JavaScript. My team and I pair programmed the entire application. ERDs and wireframes were used to layout out the structure of the app as well as map complex data relationships. The project employed basic user based CRUD functionality with the ability to login and register new users, send messages, and create new events.
- Created a follow up project to Nutshell called "HexBook" utilizing React as well as webpacks and styling libraries such as Reactstrap, Bootstrap, and Semantic UI.
- Developed a console app called "Trestlebridge Farms" utilizing C# .NET framework that kept track of inventory for a farm.
- Created several different versions of an Amazon-style full stack ecommerce application utilizing MVC and Entity frameworks as well as SQL databases.

DRIVEMATCH JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

June 2020 - current

- Currently doing contract work as a junior developer for a start up company that matches freelance truck drivers with jobs posted by carriers looking to hire. Working in React Native, Node.js, and Typescript.
- Projects tackled include fixing code that parses data from various forms of drivers licenses. Wrote node scripts to print incoming data in order to analyze what fields were empty and not parsing correctly. Successfully solved the problem by writing code in Javascript that properly formatted data according to trends noted in analysis.

Professional Work Experience

WIT COURIER **MEDICAL COURIER**

July 2016 - August 2019

• Worked for a small medical courier company that handled all of the highly sensitive delivery items such as medication, blood work, and lab charts for Tennessee Oncology. Learned to handle detailed logistical situations as well as meet the tight deadlines of the fast paced healthcare industry.

IOELTON MIDDLE SCHOOL MUSIC TEACHER

August 2015 - May 2016

 Taught 7th and 8th graders with engaging original lesson plans that involved reading music, exposure to various world music styles, and creative collaboration in small teams.